mathworksheets4kids.com 2019-05-05

# Privacy Policy

In adherence to the General Data Protection Regulation passed by the EU with regard to data protection and privacy, we have made a few amendments to our privacy policy. Our privacy policy gives a brief overview on what kind of information is collected by mathworksheets4kids.com, how it is being used, and the measures taken to safeguard it.

**What information do we collect and why?**

Mathworksheets4kids takes matters with regard to the privacy of users very seriously. We are responsible for the Personally Identifiable Information (PII), which a user discloses to us when information is shared.

This personal information is collected only when you are registered as a user on our website. Once you register with us, we collect your first name, last name, address, ZIP code, phone number, user name and password, (created by you) to provide you an authentic access to our website. If you choose to subscribe to our website, the transactions will be via Pay Pal or credit card. Your credit card details will never be saved in our server.

We collect the details of the state and the country from which you log in. We use log files to identify a visitor's IP address, ISP (Internet Service Provider), demographic information, date and time of visit, and the number of hits on our website. For security reasons these data are collected to monitor and block suspicious IP addresses.

We collect user address details for the purpose of generating payment receipt and to autofill the same information when a subscriber chooses to renew his subscription. User email address is retained only for the purpose of official communication and promotional offers. This data is retained until the last date of subscription; after which the data is deleted from our server.

We also retain your feedback and suggestions received over e-mail to improve upon our products and our website, thereby providing you high-quality worksheets.

All the above information collected is used primarily to render the best possible service and to simplify the transaction processes.

**Third-party disclosure**

We do not sell, rent or share the details of your personal information to third-party vendors.

**Google, our trusted third-party vendor**

Google, a third party vendor, uses the DART cookie to serve ads to our users based on their visits to our website, www.mathworksheets4kids.com .Users may control the use of the DART cookie by visiting the Google ad and content network privacy policy, details of which are available in the following URL - _<https://policies.google.com/technologies/ads>_

Google AdSense and Google certified third-party vendors or ad networks may use cookies, JavaScript or web beacons on our site to measure the effectiveness of their advertisements and/or to personalize the advertising content that you see. Google Ad-sense also displays certified third-party vendors and networks ads. _[List of third-party vendors and ad networks](https://support.google.com/adsense/answer/94149?hl=en)_

These third-party ad servers or ad networks use various technologies to deliver advertisements. Links that appear on _Math worksheets 4 kids_ are sent directly to your browsers. They automatically receive your IP address when this occurs. 

If you would like to know your choices about not having such information being used, kindly consult the privacy policy of _[Google.](https://policies.google.com/privacy)_

**How do we protect your information?**

We scan our website on a regular basis to ensure your visits are always secure. Your personal information is contained behind secured networks, and we use 256-bit SSL (Secure Socket Layer) technology where all your personal information solicited at the time of subscription is encrypted.

Various security measures are taken to safeguard your personal information. All transactions are processed through a secured payment gateway. 

**Do we use cookies?**

We utilize only Google cookies solely for the purpose of tracking the number of visitors to our website. Our web server recognizes only the IP address and not a visitor's Email ID. This information is used for internal analysis and is then disposed off. 

Here is a list of cookies that are used on our website:

**_utm.gif :** Google Analytics uses a tracking code that logs details about the visitors browser and computer.

**_utma :** Collects data on the number of times a user has visited the website as well as dates for the first and most recent visit. Used by Google Analytics.

**_utmb :** Registers a timestamp with the exact time of when the user accesses the website. Used by Google Analytics to calculate the duration of a website visit.

**_utmc :** Registers a timestamp with the exact time of when the user leaves the website. Used by Google Analytics to calculate the duration of a website visit.

**_utmt :** Used to throttle the speed of requests to the server. 

**_utmz :** Collects data on where the user's IP address, what search engines were used, what link was clicked and what search term was used. Used by Google Analytics.

**d :** Collects anonymous data on the user's visit to the website, such as the number of visits, average time spent on the website and what pages have been loaded with the purpose of generating reports for optimizing the website content.

**How to change cookie settings?**

You may change your cookie settings in your browser. If you choose to delete, disable or block cookies will affect the functionality and certain features on our website; thereby impacting user experience. Feel free to access any of the links below to deactivate cookies from your respective browser :

_[➔ Internet explorer](https://support.microsoft.com/en-us/help/17442/windows-internet-explorer-delete-manage-cookies)_

_[➔ Firefox](https://support.mozilla.org/en-US/kb/enable-and-disable-cookies-website-preferences)_

_[➔ Chrome](https://support.google.com/chrome/answer/95647)_

_[➔ Safari](https://support.apple.com/kb/ph21411?locale=en_IN)_

**Google Analytics**

Google Analytics is a service provider for web analytics owned by Google.Inc. They utilize cookies to help us analyze how users use our website. This information is used to improve user experience on our website. For more information about Google Analytics cookies, please see their help page & privacy policy:

_[➔ Google's privacy policy](https://policies.google.com/privacy)_

_[➔ Google Analytics help page](https://support.google.com/analytics/answer/6004245?hl=en)_

If you wish to opt out of Google Analytics, you can download and install the add-on for your web browser:

_[➔ Add-on](https://tools.google.com/dlpage/gaoptout)_

**Protection of children's privacy**

The U.S. Congress passed the Children's Online Privacy Protection Act (COPPA), 1998. This applies to the collection of personal information from children below the age of 13. The legislation allows parents or guardians to review personal information collected from their children. 

A similar clause under Article 8, GDPR passed by the EU states that processing of personal data of a child below 16 years is subject to parental consent. If any information is furnished by a child ranging between the ages of 13 and 16 as the case may be, please write to us to retrieve the information. 

**Your consent**

Upon subscription, you consent to our websites' privacy policy. Please accept our privacy policy to subscribe to our website.

**Other Information**

In case of any complaint with regard to any perceived misuse of personal information, a subscriber can e-mail us at the address below or use our _Feedback form._

This privacy policy is subject to change from time to time. If you have any queries regarding our privacy policy, drop in an email to our technical support team at _[webmistress@mathworksheets4kids.com.](mailto:webmistress@mathworksheets4kids.com)_
